# ADITYA ARORA

Engineering Undergraduate

# PERSONAL INFO:

Address BG - 6, 63 - B, Paschim Vihar, New Delhi - 110063, India

Phone 8375059963

E-mail contact@adityaarora.info

**Date of birth** 1998-01-06

LinkedIn https://linkedin.com/in/aditya-arora-124aba142/

#### HADD CKILLE.

• HTML

CSS

Python

MATLAB

JQuery

AngularJS

C/C++

LateX

• Microsoft Office

DBMS

#### DIBLICATIONS:

November 2018

A Non-invasive Framework for Detecting Hypercholesterolemia using Computer Vision - IJEDR

November 2018

A Novel Non-invasive Framework for Predicting Bilirubin Levels - Springer (LNCSE)

March 2019

Advanced Anti-theft and Accident Alert System for Two Wheelers using Location Based Services - Springer (LNEE) A diligent worker with a very focused and result oriented approach. Good at communication and understanding along with high emotional intelligence. Always up to learning new technologies and approaches with prior experience of working in a number of organizations and providing client basis services.

# **EXPERIENCES:**

## **FULL STACK DEVELOPER INTERN**

Capital One Technologies March 2019 to present

- Redesigned the official website of TrackInIndia by Capital One.
- Developed of a Web Application for handling all client requests, integration of database entries with automated emails.
- Developed an employee login portal for providing single step solutions to the needs of the operations team.

#### **RESEARCH INTERN**

Indian Institute of Technology Delhi June 2018 to July 2018

- Developed simulation models on MATLAB for MAC layer of Visible Light Communication.
- Tested multilayered Visible Light Communication simulation models on NS3.
- Performed rigorous literature surveys for Visible Light Communication technology.

#### **TEACHING INTERN**

Aashman Foundation June 2017 to August 2017

- · Mentored and taught underprivileged children.
- Recruited underprivileged children for providing them the necessary educational resources.
- · Carried out donation drives.

#### **EDUCATION:**

St. Sophia Senior Secondary School, New Delhi - Class of 2016

- 10th class CGPA 9.6
- 12th class percentage 88.88%

Bharati Vidyapeeth's College of Engineering, New Delhi - Class of 2020

• CGPA (upto 4th semester) - 8.66

#### **CERTIFICATES:**

January 2019

KitsNSpares - Winter training program in Internet of Things.

November 2018

Conference - ICCVBIC 2018 (RV College of Engineering, Coimbatore, India)

January 2019

Intellectual Property Workshop - MHRD's IIC BVCoE, New Delhi, India

All India Rank 3 - Global Science Olympiad 2015

# **ADDITIONAL ACTIVITIES:**

#### **BVPIEEE**

August 2017 - present

- Web Administrator (2018 present) at BVPIEEE, created the branch's website from scratch. Managed the executive team consisting of 3 members.
- Event Manager (2018 present) at BVPIEEE.
- Event Manager (2017-18) at BVPIEEE RAS.

#### WEB DEVELOPER (VOLUNTEER)

Amoli Trust

December 2018 to January 2019

- Created the web design for the website of the organization.
- Developed the entire website using HTML, CSS, JS, and PHP.
- Managed SEO related tasks and server side management for the website.

## FREELANCER - WEB DESIGN AND DEVELOPMENT

2017 - present

Delivered multiple number of sites to clients designed using HTML, CSS, JS, PHP, Django, Wordpress.

- SSP Enviro Solutions https://sspenvirosolutions.in
- RKB Ortho International https://rkbortho.com, etc.